# Spencer J. Nolton

## C# .NET Full Stack Developer

sjnolton@gmail.com | (586) 556-1764 | Royal Oak, MI Website || LinkedIn || GitHub

### **SUMMARY**

Life-long learner that is dedicated to the evolving industry of software development. After 6 years studying and practicing education, I have discovered that my greatest learning potential is in software development. There are many parallels between the endless learning curve of a professional musician and a professional developer. Once I realized this, I enrolled in the Grand Circus C# .NET bootcamp where I have developed console applications, web applications, APIs, and full-stack applications. This experience provided intense motivation to continue exploring the possibilities of code outside of class time, and I am excited to take that motivation further to pursue this career.

#### **EDUCATION**

Grand Circus Coding Bootcamp - Detroit, MI June 2022 – December 2022 Full Stack C# .NET Certificate Notable Projects

Boots N' Cats: Demo | Backend Repository | Frontend Repository

• Full-Stack web app using Spotify's Web API as well as our own.

Library Terminal: Repository

• Simulates an electronic library in a C# console application.

SpotifyPlus: Repository

• Collaborator and consultant for In-development application.

Central Michigan University - Mount Pleasant, MI August 2015 – May 2020 Bachelor's Degree in Music Education

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

• C#

.NET Core

ASP.NET

Angular/Typescript

Git/GitHub

SQL/SSMS

MVC

• Entity Framework

• HTML/CSS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager

Dessert Oasis Coffee Roasters, Royal Oak, MI

August 2021 – Present

- Managing team workflow; addressing lapses in work, effectively communicating w/ coworkers & mgmt.
- Contributing to & working on various collaborative projects around the cafe. establishing systems/structures.
- Maintaining inventory numbers & replenishing stock on both a weekly & monthly basis.

Elementary Music Teacher

Clarkston Community Schools, Clarkston, MI

October 2020 - August 2021

- Taught general music to students Pre-K through 5th grade.
- Developed new and unique instructional opportunities for students in an evolving environment.
- Collaborated with teachers district-wide on improving the instructional potential of Clarkston's music program.